Mickey Pashov

+447857984237, pashov.m@gmail.com, github.com/mickeypash

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer with professional Python experience, and interest in DevOps. My main area of expertise is cloud native Python-based microservices, with mixtures of REST API and RPC communication, that use Docker and Kubernetes to be built and deployed on AWS. I have used a combination of RDBMSes including PostgreSQL and Oracle. And have experience using Google Cloud PubSub and AWS SQS as messaging systems.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug 2018 - Present

Software Engineer, Ometria

London

- Automation and continual improvement of core data pipeline processes (Docker, Kubernetes)
- Performing large scale load tests on various parts of the system (Postgres, Python)
- Large scale performance enhancement on email sending capability (AWS)
- Mentoring and on-boarding new members of the team

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

Associate Software Engineer, JP Morgan

Glasgow

- Worked on Public Cloud Enablement Services (PCESv1) building a multi-cloud cloud provisioning service built to support AWS
- Developed Terraform provider POC
- Implemented a simple RBAC system for the RESTful API
- Added automated deployment for various services via Jenkins
- Gained experience in Python and Python web frameworks

Sep 2015 - Dec 2018

Analyst Software Engineer, JP Morgan

Glasgow

- Designed and implemented a business analysis tool, which extracted complex infrastructure and software package metadata and displayed it in a consumable way. (Java Spring Boot, Python pandas)
- Introduced the team to automated testing using Selenium and proposed a Page Object Model for faster development. (Java, Selenium)
- Developed the host availability management feature within a self-service portal for IT operations. (Java, Struts2, Twitter Bootstrap)

EDUCATION

Sep 2014 - Sep 2015

University of Glasgow, MSc Information Technology, Merit

Glasgow

- Undertook courses on Advanced Programming, Internet Technologies, Software Engineering, Enterprise Computing, Trends in Information Security
- Awarded vacation scholarship with the School of Information Retrieval

Sep 2010 - Jul 2014

University of Glasgow, BSc Psychology Honours

Glasgow

 Undertook courses on Java Programming, Python Programming, Object Oriented Software Engineering, Algorithms and Data Structures, Leadership alongside relevant degree courses

SKILLS

Python

Kubernetes

Java

Docker

RESTful APIs

Microservice Architecture

UNIX

AWS